### **Jack Havery**

39 Chaise Meadow Heatley Mere Lymm WA13 9NX

Mobile: 07837 231225 E-mail: haveryjack@gmail.com

I am experienced, personable and truly passionate about technology, design and aviation. After working for some time as an Operations Manager & Flight Training Coordinator for a flight school and charter operator, an IT Service Operations analyst, and finally as an Infrastructure Technician. Because of this, I am ready to take the next step in my IT career.

## **WORK HISTORY**

The Fragrance Shop

May 2018 - Present

I am currently employed by The Fragrance Shop as an Infrastructure Support Technician, meaning that I, and 1 other colleague, are responsible for an estate of around 200 stores, each with EPOS systems, bespoke retail data gathering software and Back Office PC's in addition to maintaining a network infrastructure for around 150 head office users, spread across 2 sites. As a result of this, I am responsible for:

- Office 365 User management & application deployment
- MS Azure server maintenance
- MZ Azure Active Directory user management
- Fortigate VPN configuration for remote users
- Cisco Meraki WAP configuration
- Meraki MDM configuration and deployment
- Commissioning and decommissioning of physical servers
- Panasonic PBX analogue phone system management and maintenance
- Maintenance and deployment of in-house warehouse management & stock control software
- Warehouse checkout & dispatch machine deployment and maintenance
- Cisco Meraki management and Access Point deployment
- Fortinet firewall and VPN administration
- IT equipment purchasing and supplier relationship management
- Sage 50 Cloud Payroll server migration and administration
- Hyper-v and VMWare VM management
- Dell Wyse thin client deployment and maintenance
- HPE and Dell Server and SAN configuration, deployment and maintenance
- Synology SAN management

In addition to the above, I have also managed a number of projects for use within the business, the latest of which has been the procurement, testing and deployment of mobile 4G dual-sim WAN routers for use across the country. This is being rolled out as of early 2019 after a period of successful testing. Early on in my time at TFS, I was also granted Domain Admin rights across the estate's servers, showing a high level of trust in my capabilities by the SMT. I am also now heavily involved in the forward planning processes of the business, forecasting future necessary hardware changes and upgrades, as well as planning and executing these upgrades with minimum impact to the business.

I am also the currently responsible individual in place of the previous IT manager who left the business, managing a small team of IT support personnel, and reporting directly into the COO. In my role as interim IT manager, I was also responsible for a small team of staff and had to manage the day-to-day running of the business critical servers. As part of this, I was on call 24/7/365, and was required to assist in bringing any failed systems back online.

### **Think Money Group**

### March 2017-May 2018

I have worked as a Service Operations Analyst for Think Money Group since March 2017 stated. I began as a 1<sup>st</sup> Line Support, learning about Active Directory and user management for the in-house applications developed for the business. As the business progressed, and teams were amalgamated, we picked up more of the development and troubleshooting side of IT Support. After 2 months of working as a 1<sup>st</sup> Line technician, the business' 2<sup>nd</sup> and 3<sup>rd</sup> line teams resigned and moved on to other opportunities, meaning that myself, and the other members of my team, were required to take on the 2<sup>nd</sup> Line responsibilities. These include:

- Active Directory user management
- SQL Prompt and Database Management query running

- PROMON and SCOM alerting and resolving
- Server Maintenance
- PC hardware building, imaging and deployment
- As the business uses iOS devices, I have been tasked with the setup and maintenance of approximately 100 iOS devices from iPhone's to the Marketing team's iMac's and MacBook's
- Supporting in-house applications setup for the FCA regulated sectors of the business
- Liaising with 3<sup>rd</sup> Party Vendors to integrate 3<sup>rd</sup> party systems into our in-house applications
- Network patching
- SCCM Software Deployments
- Group policy management
- Management of hardware assets (mobiles, PC's, laptops and tablets)
- Ticket management via ESD and ServiceNow
- Disaster recovery exercises off-site setup and support
- Basic OS image creation for use with device builds
- Ad-hoc technological consultancy for Senior Management teams

# Flight Academy Ltd 2011-February 2017

I was the Operations Manager & Flight Training Coordinator of Flight Academy Limited, based at City Airport Manchester. The company operates Helicopters and Gyrocopters, specializing in Private Charter, Flight Experiences and Flying Lessons. My job role required pricing, booking and organising private, photography and film charters. It was important to always look presentable and to communicate points and instructions clearly, especially with regards to safety of customers before and after their flight. I had to ensure that all passengers received a thorough pre-flight briefing prior for the flight itself, demonstrating the correct procedures in entering and exiting the aircraft safely.

As well as this, I assisted with looking after the company's aircraft maintenance system. This role required the use of Microsoft Excel as well as keeping and organising paper records to determine when aircraft are due for scheduled and un-scheduled maintenance.

#### **SKILLS**

I spent 8 years working at Flight Academy Ltd, beginning as a Weekend Apprentice Ground Operative, working up to becoming Operations Manager & Flight Training Coordinator for the company for the past 3 years. As such, I have first-hand experience of how a functioning flying school and charter operation is run, and have made a significant contribution in running such an organisation.

After this, I was employed by Think Money Group as a Service Operations Analyst. This has enabled me to develop my "on the phone" troubleshooting and diagnosis skills, as well as working to SLA's and KPI's. My development has been aided by the departure of the 2<sup>nd</sup> Line Support team, meaning that in the short time I have been with the company, I have been exposed to, and picked up, many skills which I would otherwise not have gained, the most valuable of which, I feel, has been the ability to troubleshoot and resolve a problem from beginning to end, rather than escalating a problem to a senior team. In my performance reviews, I have been consistently rated as an excellent member of the team, and have consistently excelled in customer service and Service Desk Request Ticket Fulfilment.

After being in the Air Cadets for a number of years, I joined 2137 Lymm Squadron as a Civilian Instructor. This role has given me the opportunity to teach young people about aviation as an industry specialist (based on my achievements and work history described below). It has taught me to work well in a team and developed my leadership qualities effectively through teaching a classroom of 30 students. I have learnt to work efficiently under pressure when organizing lectures and outdoor activities at short notice.

### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- I currently hold a full EASA (European Aviation Safety Administration) Private Helicopter Pilot's License and a full U.K Private Gyrocopter Pilot's License
- I have a full, clean, U.K Driving License, and my own car.
- I am a Civilian Instructor at 145 Altrincham and Hale Squadron Air Training Corps.
- I have obtained both my Bronze and Silver Duke of Edinburgh awards with the Air Training Corps.
- I am fully DBS (Disclosure and Barring Service) checked as a result of my involvement with the Air Training Corps.
- I am a fully qualified helicopter ground crew member, with fire and health & safety certification in accordance with a U.K AOC (Air Operators Certificate) operations manual.
- I have experience in writing, submitting and amending U.K CAA (Civil Aviation Authority) AOC (Air Operators Certificate) and Part M CAME (Continuing Airworthiness Management Exposition) manuals, as well as writing, submitting and amending Approved Aircraft Maintenance Programs.
- I deliver PPL (Private Pilot's License) ground school to helicopter and gyrocopter students on a regular basis.
- I have experience in providing charter quotes for VFR (Visual Flight Rules), U.K flights and following these quotes

through to their conclusion.

• I am also the recipient of a Blue Peter badge for my work on "Project Petra", this meant a coordinating 3 helicopters, 40 children and numerous film crew members to undertake flights around Manchester City Centre whilst also filming inside the aircraft.

## **EDUCATION AND QUALIFICATIONS**

St Ambrose Grammar School, Hale Barns 2006-2011

GCSE's

English Literature B ICT C Biology C English Language C Mathematics C Physics C

#### **INTERESTS**

As described above, I enjoy working on computers of all types, including games consoles and the Raspberry Pi family of affordable computers. I have repaired, and maintained computers for friends and family for many years, preferring not to "throw away and buy new" but rather to replace and upgrade components at a lower cost. I also very much enjoy working with the Linux-based Debian Operating System for the Raspberry Pi, and I am currently planning to implement a course for my Air Training Corps Squadron to learn how to basic code using this system. As a result of this, I am experienced in using Windows, Macintosh and Linux operating systems and as such, I am very comfortable using the entire Microsoft Office Suite.

However, aside from these interests, my absolute passion is aviation. I have loved flying since I was very young, and this prompted me to obtain a weekend job as a teenager at Flight Academy. I have met a great deal of aircraft owners and operators both based at City Airport Manchester and elsewhere, many of whom have given me the opportunity to accompany them on flights around the country. A number of owners (listed below as referees) have also entrusted me with cleaning and ground maneuvering their aircraft, as well as acting as a crew member on some flights.

I have also been trying to create a "home-lab" using my own PC and a collection of Raspberry Pi's utilizing them as DHCP servers, AD-type user management servers which has translated into creating a network of PC's with a domain at the Air Training Corps Squadron with a central server and file shares set up. My own home network also uses multiple Pi's as NAS' DHCP server etc. This has helped me to learn whilst at home, things that I can take into my day job with me.

## **REFERENCES**

<u>Stuart Adderley</u> Head of Service Delivery at Think Money stuart.adderley@thinkmoney.com

Capt. Philip Robinson
M.D. Flight Academy Ltd
info@flightacademy.co.uk
0161 788 8489